召集大军 时候到了
Summon the legions. It is time.
我们的敌人誓要进攻
Our enemy vows to attack.
你们谁愿意挺身一战？
Who among you will stand and fight?
你们会死的
You will die.
我等待这一天很久了
<i>Long have I awaited this day.</i>
我向索隆宣誓效忠
I pledge my loyalty to Sauron.
我们一半的人都走了
Half of us just left.
但还有一半选择留下
But half stayed.
我怎么没被选中参加远征？
<i>Why wasn't I chosen for the expedition?</i>
你不是想往西去嘛
Thought you were going west.
我得先做点什么 尽忠于努门诺尔
Not till I've done something worthy of Númenor.
我刚说服了努门诺尔派出五艘船
<i>I have just convinced Númenor to send five ships</i>
五百精锐 援助你的人民
<i>and 500 men to aid your people</i>
助你加冕为王
<i>and place a crown upon your head.</i>
你要让我去一个我曾发誓不会再去的地方
You are asking me to go to the one place that I swore never to return.
你为何依旧战斗？
Why do you keep fighting?
因为我无法停下
Because I cannot stop.
跟我走 我们将合力拯救各自的血脉
<i>Come with me, and together we will redeem both our bloodlines.</i>
我们朝东北行进
We head nor'-east.
前往中洲
For Middle-earth.
那可不是剑 是种力量
<i>It is no sword. It is a power.</i>
听说过索隆吗?
Have you heard of Sauron?
我曾见过它
<i>I've seen this before.</i>
这是把钥匙
<i>It is a key.</i>
大敌以失传法术所制 用于奴役你的先祖
<i>The enemy commander spoke of giving the Orcs a home in these lands.</i>
但不论他有何企图 毋庸置疑的是
<i>Whatever his design, this much is certain.</i>
敌人知道你儿子有他启动计划所需的东西
<i>Our enemy knows your son has what he needs to enact it.</i>
还有多久?
<i>How long?</i>
也许几小时
<i>Maybe hours.</i>
以新生
<i>Vinya coivie</i>
对抗死亡
<i>nat fírie.</i>
我的孩子们
My children,
我们历经无数艰辛
we have endured much.
我们挣脱了枷锁
We cast off our shackles.
跨过高山和田野
Crossed mountain, field,
穿越严寒与荒地
frost, and fallow
直到脚上的血浸染了泥土
till our feet bloodied the dirt.
从埃瑞德米斯林到埃斐尔阿尔能
From <i>Ered Mithrin</i> to the <i>Ephel Arnen,</i>
我们都挺过来了
we have endured.
然而今晚 还有一场考验等待着我们
Yet tonight, one more trial awaits us.
我们的敌人可能势单力薄
Our enemy may be weak, their numbers meager...
但在今夜结束之前 我们中有些会倒下
...yet before this night is through, some of us will fall.
然而这一次 当你们倒下时
But for the first time, you do so
将不再是远方大地上的无名奴隶
not as unnamed slaves in far-away lands,
而是彼此的兄弟
but as brothers.
以兄弟姐妹的身份 在家园的土地上倒下！
As brothers and sisters in our home!
战斗
<i>Nampat.</i>
战斗！战斗！
<i>Nampat! Nampat!</i>
就在今晚
This is the night
-我们伸出乌鲁克族的铁拳 -战斗！战斗！
- we reach out the iron hand of the <i>Uruk... - Nampat! Nampat!</i>
握紧拳头夺回这片土地
...and close our fist around these lands.
战斗！
<i>Nampat!</i>
给我搜
Search it.
全体注意！分头行动！找到他们！
All of you! Fan out! Find them!
无意顶撞 父亲大人 但他在哪？
Meaning no offense, Lord-father, but where is he?
索隆出什么事了？
What happened to Sauron?
找不到他的行踪轨迹 肯定是学聪明溜走了
Can't find tooth nor tail of him. Must've got smart and scarpered.
不 那个精灵就在这里
No. The Elf's here.
我闻到了他的气味
I smell him.
遵命 父亲
Yes, Father.
在这上面！
Up here!
拿下他！
Bring him down!
出去 快点！
Get out, now!
打开那扇门！
Open that door!
快出去！
Get out!
父亲大人！您得马上离开！
Lord-father! You must move now!
您得离开！
You must move!
有几个挨了这一下还能活下来？
How many of 'em could have survived that?
我们还有多少时间？
How long do we have?
没多少了
Not long enough.
来吧 我们必须做好准备
Come on, we have to make ready the village.
别紧张 贝瑞克 放松
Easy, Berek. Easy, boy.
升帆！
Hoist it up!
我以为现在是全体士兵的就寝时间
I thought all soldiers were to be abed.
对不起 指挥官 我 我只是…
Pardon me, Commander. I... I was only...
想第一个看到陆地？
Hoping to get the first sight of land?
稍息
At ease.
过一会儿你们就看得到了
It'll be visible to your eyes in a few moments.
您已经看到了吗？
Is it visible to yours already?
一小时前就看到了
Has been for nearly an hour.
精灵的眼睛真是敏锐
Keen are the eyes of the Elves.
可我还从未见过你
And yet, mine have not before seen you.
你既不使剑又不挂帆
Swinging steel nor flying sail.
你是什么军衔？
What is your rank?
扫马厩的
Stable sweep.
不要轻视使心灵谦卑的劳动
Despise not the labor which humbles the heart.
谦卑曾拯救诸多王国 骄傲却只能致其覆灭
Humility has saved entire kingdoms the proud have all but led to ruin.
我加入此次远征可不是来学会谦卑的 指挥官
I did not join this expedition to be humbled, Commander.
那是为了什么 士兵？
Then for what did you join, soldier?
我只是想逃走
I was just trying to get away.
离那里越远越好
As far as I could from that place.
努门诺尔？
Númenor?
它不是努门诺尔
It's not Númenor.
反正不是真正的努门诺尔
Not the real Númenor, anyway.
如果它真的存在过
If it ever existed.
它当然存在过
It existed.
它依然存在
It exists still...
即便是在最卑微的马厩清扫者心中
If only in the heart of the lowliest stable sweep.
我是伊熙尔杜
It's Isildur.
我本该知道的
I might have known.
你与你父亲容貌相似
You have the look of your father.
人们总是说我更像母亲
I was always told I look more like my mother.
士兵
Soldier.
长官
Captain.
他的母亲
His mother...
她怎么了？
What happened to her?
真是奇怪
It is strange.
我此前半生 总是东望旭日跃于海面
Most of my life, I've looked east to see the Sun rise over the sea.
西观落日沉入远山
And west to see it set over the land.
我们正驶入黎明 然而 对我而言
We're sailing into the dawn, and yet, to me,
感觉却像夜幕降临
it feels like the coming of night.
她溺水而死
She drowned.
看到陆地了 陛下
<i>Land has been sighted, Your Majesty.</i>
还有多久可以下锚？
<i>How long before we make anchor?</i>
要抵达山脉还有一整天的航程
It's a full day's sail into the mountains.
从那里出发 还需向东骑行一天到达山谷
And from there, another day's ride east into the vale.
给其他船只发信号
Signal the other ships.
告诉他们全速前进
Tell them to make all possible haste.
我们无法摧毁它
It is beyond our skill to destroy.
你要把它藏到哪里？
Where will you hide it?
不能让任何人知道
No one must know.
连你也不行
Not even you.
我们已经发现敌人
<i>Our enemy has been sighted.</i>
我们曾从他们手中逃过一劫
<i>We survived them before.</i>
现在我们也要如此
<i>Now we must do so again.</i>
就在今晚
Tonight.
我们占据了地利
Our position gives us an advantage.
但若想利用它 就必须诱敌深入
<i>But to use it, we must draw the enemy in close.</i>
我们必须等所有奥克跨过那座桥
We must wait until every last Orc
再发起进攻
has crossed that bridge to spring our attack.
这对你们的勇气是个考验
<i>This will test your nerve.</i>
沉住气
<i>Let it.</i>
所有无法战斗的人员都要在里面驻守
All who cannot fight will be barricaded inside.
这里是我们的要塞 我们的最后据点
This is to be our keep. Our fallback point.
所有人 振作起来
Take heart. All of you.
我见过更单薄的兵力在更悬殊的场合取胜
I have seen smaller armies defeat greater foes.
不久 日落将至
Soon, the sun will set.
诸位各尽所能 我保证 你们还能看到旭日重升
Do your part, and I swear to you, you shall see it rise again.
-你们有信心吗？-有
- Do you believe it? - Aye.
-有信心吗？-有！
- Do you believe it? - Aye!
各就各位
To your positions.
我呢？
What about me?
去酒馆
Tavern.
酒馆是留给伤患和孩童的 我能战斗
Tavern's for wounded and children. I can fight.
我知道你能
I know you can.
所以我要你待在那里 保护不能战斗的人
Which is why I need you in there, protecting those who cannot.
来吧
Come.
还记得我小时候 常做噩梦吗？
Remember when I was little... When I used to have bad dreams?
我记得
I remember.
你还记得你以前说的吗？
You remember what you used to say?
当你在黑暗中抱着我的时候？
When you would hold me in the dark?
现在可以再说给我听听吗？
Would you say it to me now?
魔影终归只是渺小之物  且会逝去
"""In the end, this shadow is but a small and passing thing.
而在魔影无法触及之处
"""There is light and high beauty
光明与崇高的美永存
"""forever beyond its reach.
去寻找光明吧
"""Find the light...
如此魔影便永远不得临身
"""And the shadow will not find you.""
再会 母亲
Farewell, Mother.
你准备好了吗
<i>Are you ready?</i>
没有 你呢
No. Are you?
阿尔费琳种子
The <i>alfirin</i> seeds...
这是精灵的一项传统
It is a tradition among Elves.
在上战场前 种下一颗
Before the battle begins, plant one.
以新生 对抗死亡？
New life, in defiance of death?
我们相信有一位维拉
It is believed that one of the Valar
照看一切生长之物
watches over growing things...
以及播种照料它们的人
And those who tend them.
剩下的种子
The rest...
我们等战争结束后再种吧
we shall plant after the battle is over.
在新生的花园里
In a new garden.
你和我
You and I.
还有希奥
And Theo.
我们一起
Together.
答应我
Promise me.
他们来了
They're here.
老天啊
Oh, dear...
这群待宰的蠢货没击中我们
The bleeding fools missed us.
冲啊！
Come on!
他们往酒馆那边去了
They're headed for the tavern.
-为了南境而战！-为了南境而战！
- Fight for the Southlands! - Fight for the Southlands!
这片土地是我们的！
The land is ours!
英勇可嘉 精灵 简直万夫莫当
More than a bit brave, Elf. More than a bit.
布隆玟
Bronwyn.
我们是在和自己人作战
We were fighting our own.
你以为我们会白白收留他们？
Thought we'd take 'em in for nothin'?
这可是有代价的
Had to pay the toll...
现在 你们都要付出代价了
And now, all of you will.
特雷德威尔！
Tredwill!
妈妈！
Mother!
所有人 躲进要塞！
Everyone, to the keep!
跑！快跑！
Go! Go!
到酒馆里去！
Into the tavern!
快进酒馆！
The tavern!
全都进去！
All of you!
快来！
Go!
桌子！
The table!
快！
Hurry!
快点！
妈妈 妈妈
Mother. Mother.
先去救他
Help him first.
不要啊
No.
我们会救你的
We will help you.
妈妈
Mother.
希奥
Theo...
你得赶紧止血
You'll have to stem the bleeding.
我 我不行
I... I don't think I...
你要是做不到 我会死 你明白吗？
Either you're gonna do this or I'm gonna die. Do you understand?
希奥
Theo.
母亲 做好准备
Mother, prepare yourself.
抱歉了
I am sorry.
快压住伤口
Put pressure on the wound.
烧
Burn...
她好冷 她失血过多了
She's cold. She's lost too much blood.
不 不 不
No. No. No.
她说「烧」
"She's saying ""burn.""
用阿尔费琳种子 用火来烧结伤口
The <i>alfirin</i> seeds. We have to seal the wound with fire.
拿些烧着的木头来 快！
Bring me some burning wood. Hurry!
现在
Now.
就是现在
换这边
Now this side.
继续
Go on.
应该够了
That's enough.
布隆玟？
Bronwyn?
-母亲？-布隆玟？
- Mother? - Bronwyn?
醒醒！母亲！
Wake up! Mother!
战斗！
<i>Nampat!</i>
从背后痛击他们！
<i>Kick 'em in the back!</i>
战斗！
<i>Nampat!</i>
坐下！
Sit down!
我要找的东西
<i>Sana i cestan,</i>
把它给我
<i>áse anta nin.</i>
放了他们
<i>Áte sene...</i>
我会考虑
<i>ar uvuvan sa.</i>
何必为如此微不足道的东西 赔上他们的性命？
Why sacrifice their lives for such a little thing?
那女人是下一个
The woman next.
不！
No!
-等等！-希奥！
- Wait! - Theo!
在地板下面
It's under here.
不
No.
希奥！
Theo!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
沃尔德雷格 我有件任务给你
Waldreg, I have a task for you.
他们都得死
They all must die.
昂塔莫！
Ontamo!
去吧
Go.
驾！
Hyah!
父亲！
Father!
-我没事 -我以为你…
- I'm all right. - I thought you...
我没事 伊熙尔
I'm all right, Isil.
士兵
<I>Mahtar.</i>
敌首何在？
Their commander?
他所持之物
<i>I maryasse…</i>
绝不可被他带走
<i>vá usuva se asse.</i>
她是谁？
Who is that?
北方军的指挥官
Commander of the Northern Armies.
加拉德瑞尔
Galadriel.
快跑！
<i>Noro lim!</i>
还记得我吗？
You remember me?
不记得
No.
住手！
Stop!
我们需要活口
We need him alive.
我需要活口
I need him alive.
你不知道他做了什么
You don't know what he did.
我给你爱的人带去伤痛了吗？
Did I cause someone you love pain?
一个女人？
A woman?
或许是个孩子？
Perhaps a child?
闭嘴
Eat your tongue.
哈尔布兰德 放下武器
Halbrand, put it down.
人不能饮海水止渴
One cannot satisfy thirst by drinking sea water.
所以 你感觉如何？
So, what do you think?
我喜欢这群山
I like the mountains.
你马上就能更仔细地瞧瞧它们了
You're about to get a closer look at them.
指挥官加拉德瑞尔要召集一支队伍
Commander Galadriel's putting together a company
追踪逃走的奥克
to track down the Orcs that escaped,
而我设法为我俩挣来了位置
and I managed to wheedle the pair of us a spot.
昂塔莫呢？
What about Ontamo?
我想我会在这儿待一阵 帮帮这群伙计
I think I might stay here for a while. Lend these folk a hand.
-受够了一周的战斗？-这辈子都够了
- Seen enough battle for a week? - More like a whole lifetime.
这支队伍何时动身？
This company, when's it set out?
还不确定 得等她处置好他再说
Don't know for certain. Not till she's done with him.
我孩童时期 听过精灵被魔苟斯带走的故事
When I was a child, I heard stories of Elves taken by Morgoth.
他们被折磨 扭曲
Tortured. Twisted.
被塑造成新的 被摧残的生命形式
Made into a new and ruined form of life.
你也是其中一员 对吗？
You are one of them, are you not?
魔里昂多
The Moriondor.
黑暗之子
The Sons of the Dark.
最初的奥克
The first Orcs.
乌鲁克
<i>Uruk.</i>
我们更愿意自称「乌鲁克」
"We prefer <i>""Uruk.""</i>
即使是魔里昂多也要听从主上号令
Even Moriondor take orders from a master.
我要找的正是你的主人
And I seek yours.
他在何处？
Where is he?
索隆在何处？
Where is Sauron?
或许我们该让囚犯晒晒太阳
Perhaps we should bring our prisoners into the sunlight.
魔苟斯败退之后
After Morgoth's defeat,
你们称之为「索隆」的那位
the one you call Sauron...
致力于「治愈」中洲
Devoted himself to healing Middle-earth,
令被伤毁的大地重归完满与秩序
bringing its ruined lands together in perfect order.
他试图创造出一种力量
He sought to craft a power
不局限于血肉之躯
not of the flesh...
而是远超其上
But over flesh.
来自幽界的力量
A power of the Unseen World.
他尽力笼络追随者 一路北行
He bid as many as he could to follow him far north.
可尽管他竭尽所能
But try as he might...
仍缺少一样东西
Something was missing.
它隐藏在黑暗术法的阴影里
<i>A shadow of dark knowledge</i>
即便是他也无处找寻
<i>that kept itself hidden, even from him.</i>
哪怕他的找寻之路已经鲜血淋漓
<i>No matter how much blood he spilt in its pursuit.</i>
至于我
Mmm. For my part...
为了他的欲望 我已经牺牲了太多孩子
I sacrificed enough of my children for his aspirations.
我将他开膛破腹
I split him open.
我杀了索隆
I killed Sauron.
我不信
I do not believe you.
你当然不信一个乌鲁克能杀了他
You cannot believe an <i>Uruk</i> could do that
毕竟你们整支大军都无法做到
which your entire army could not.
我不相信你是这支军队唯一的主人
I cannot believe that you are this army's only master.
我的孩子没有主人
My children have no master.
他们不是孩子 他们是奴隶
They are not children, they are slaves.
但他们每一个都有名字
But each one has a name. A heart.
都有心
A heart.
-魔苟斯创造的心 -我们是独一之神的造物
- A heart created by Morgoth. - We are creations of The One,
出自秘火主宰之手 同你们一样
Master of the Secret Fire, the same as you.
他们值得这一息生命
As worthy of the breath of life,
也值得一个家
and just as worthy of a home.
很快
Soon...
这片土地将属于我们 到那时你就会明白
This land will be ours. Then, you will understand.
不
No.
你们一族是个错误
Your kind was a mistake.
是拙劣的仿品
Made in mockery.
哪怕要花上整个纪元 我也发誓要将你们铲除殆尽
And even if it takes me all of this Age, I vow to eradicate every last one of you.
但我会留你一命
But you shall be kept alive,
等到那一天
so that one day,
在我的匕首刺入你腐坏的心脏之前
before I drive my dagger into your poisoned heart,
我会在你的尖耳朵旁低语
I will whisper in your piked ear
说你的后代无一存活
that all your offspring are dead
你们一族的祸根于你终结
and the scourge of your kind ends with you.
看来我不是唯一一个活着
It would seem I'm not the only Elf alive
却已经被黑暗转化的精灵
who has been transformed by darkness.
也许你所寻觅的魔苟斯的继任者
Perhaps your search for Morgoth's successor
最终会出现在你的镜中倒影里
should have ended in your own mirror.
也许我该先杀了你 你这流涎的奥克
Perhaps I shall begin by killing you, you slavering Orc.
加拉德瑞尔
Galadriel.
乌鲁克
<i>Uruk.</i>
你是谁
Who are you?
谢谢你
Thank you...
把我拉了回来
For pulling me back.
之前是你把我拉了回来
Was you, pulled me back first.
不管他对你做了什么
Whatever it was he did to you,
也不管你做了什么
and whatever it was you did...
都要放下
Be free of it.
我从没觉得我能放下
I never believed I could be...
直到今天
Until today.
与你并肩作战 我
Fighting at your side, I...
我觉得
I felt...
如果我能抓住这种感觉
If I could just hold on to that feeling,
时刻带在身边
keep it with me always,
将它与我的灵魂紧紧相连 那么我
bind it to my very being, then I...
我也有同样的感受
I felt it, too.
哈尔布兰德大人
Lord Halbrand.
执政女王想要见您
The Queen Regent wishes to see you.
执政女王
Queen Regent.
我欠你的 我的族人因你才得以生存
What I owe you... My people are alive because of you.
在我看来 他们能活下来是因为你
As I understand it, they're alive because of you.
我从未想过要背负这样的重担
A burden I never sought to take up.
那些最优秀的领袖也是一样
Few of the finest leaders do.
不过 如果你想减轻一点负担
But if you would like some relief in carrying it,
或许我可以帮忙
I may be able to help.
您在找我 殿下？
You called for me, Your Majesty?
布隆玟
Bronwyn...
这位是哈尔布兰德大人
This is Lord Halbrand.
布隆玟
Bronwyn.
是真的吗？你就是我们应许的国王？
Is it true? Are you the king we were promised?
是
Yes.
致敬吧！
All hail!
向真正的南境之王致敬！
All hail to the true King of the Southlands!
这片土地上的人们等待这一刻很久了
The men of these lands have awaited this moment a long time.
远不及精灵等得久
Not nearly so long as the Elves.
不要折磨自己了
Do not torment yourself.
在那种处境下 很多人都会这么做
Many might have done the same in your place.
你不懂
You don't understand.
不仅仅是愧疚
It's not just guilt I feel.
还有失落
It's loss.
失落？
Loss?
当它在我手中
When it was in my hands,
我感受到了
I felt...
力量
Powerful.
那就摆脱它吧
Then rid yourself of it.
彻底摆脱
Once and for all.
怎么做？
How?
把它交给努门诺尔人
Give it to Númenor.
让他们在返乡途中丢进大海
To toss into the sea on their voyage home.
冷静点 贝瑞克 冷静
Easy. Berek, easy.
只是擦伤 没事的
It's just a scratch. You're okay.
嘿 贝瑞克
Hey, hey, hey. Berek.
小心
Careful.
安静点
<i>Athae… no ídhui hí.</i>
你怎么做到的？
How did you do that?
困扰它的并不是自身的疼痛
It's not his pain that's bothering him...
而是骑手的
But that of his rider.
我并不觉得疼痛
I'm not in pain.
当西方之地的马踏上战场
When a horse of Westernesse rides into battle,
就会与它的骑手建立牢不可破的羁绊
he forms an unbreakable bond with the soldier he bears.
渐渐地 他们合二为一
In time, they become as one.
甚至通晓彼此内心最深处的感受
Even knowing the innermost feelings of each other's heart.
-你知道它的感受？ -不
- You know his feelings? - No.
它知道你的
He knows yours.
你从哪里学到这些的？
Where did you learn all this?
从你的母亲那里
From your mother.
你可以教我吗？
Think you could teach me?
乌顿
<i>Udûn...</i>
乌顿 乌顿
<i>Udûn. Udûn.</i>
找掩护！
Take shelter!
女王！
The Queen!
贝瑞克！
Berek!
维蓝迪尔！
Valandil!
去墙那儿！
Over the wall!
希奥！希奥！
- Theo! - Theo!